# KARIM TIT

French national, 27 years old, **?** Inria Rennes, France.

Ph.D. candidate in Machine Learning (ML), defense expected in April 2024.

☑ karim.tit@inria.fr — 🗖 karim-tit — 🗘 karimtito — 😵 karimtito.github.io — 🞓 Google Scholar profile

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Thales Land and Air Systems (LAS)

February 2021 - January 2024

ML Research Engineer, supervised by Dr. Louis-Marie Traonouez

Worked on the reliability of Deep Neural Networks for cyber-security applications.

KeyQuant

May 2020 - September 2020

Quantitative research intern, supervised by Dr. Charles Chevalier

Enhanced and implemented [in Python] trend-following trading strategies with machine learning models.

CREST, CNRS

July 2019 - September 2019

Research intern, supervised by Dr. Anna Simoni

Implemented [in R] and analyzed a new estimator for inverse problems in high dimensional econometrics.

# Capital Fund Management & École Polytechnique

March 2019 - July 2019

Quantitative research intern, supervised by Dr. Michael Benzaquen & Dr. Iacoppo Mastromatteo

Developed a financial market microstructure model for the Chair Econophysics and Complex Systems

ScreenSeed October 2018 - March 2019

Part-time R&D project, supervised by Dr. Edwin Grappin (CTO)

Computer vision research project (seeds growth prediction) using ML methods for a biotech startup.

#### EDUCATION **1**

#### INRIA & University of Rennes

February 2021- January 2024

Ph.D. in Computer Science, supervised by Dr. Teddy Furon & Dr. Mathias Rousset

Thesis subject: "Reliability of Deep Neural Networks with Rare Event Simulation Algorithms."

### Paris-Saclay University (ex Paris-XI)

2019-2020

Masters in Mathematics of Randomness (M2), StatML track highest distinction, GPA 4.0

Some relevant courses: Reinforcement Learning, Statistical Learning

#### ENSAE Paris, Polytechnic Institute Of Paris

2018-2020

Master of Engineering and Data Science (Diplôme d'ingénieur) highest distinction, GPA 4.0

Some relevant courses: Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, C++

#### Paris Sciences Et Lettres University (ex Paris-IX)

2018-2019

Research Masters in Pure and Applied Mathematics (M2) highest distinction, GPA 4.0

Some relevant courses: Stochastic Calculus, Stochastic Control

# Sorbonne University (ex Paris-VI)

2016-2018

B.Sc. in Mathematics with minor in Physics (L3), highest distinction, GPA 4.0

## Lycée Pierre Corneille

2014- 2016

Preparatory classes for the french 'Grandes écoles', focus on Mathematics

with honours, Grade A

## LANGUAGE & TECHNICAL SKILLS X

French Mother tongue

English C1 level (TOEFL: 104/120)

German B1 level

Programming languages (main), R, C++ (secondary)

Python libraries Numpy, Pandas, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn

Operating systems  $\Delta$ ,

Software tools git, , IATEX

## PUBLICATIONS 1

## Three Bricks to Consolidate Watermarks for Large Language Models. - WIFS 2023

P. Fernandez, A. Chaffin, K.T., V. Chappelier, T. Furon- IEEE 15th International Workshop on Information Forensics and Security, Dec 2023, Nuremberg, Germany.

#### Gradient-Informed Neural Network Statistical Robustness Estimation. - AISTATS 2023

K.T., T. Furon, M.Rousset. - 26th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), Apr 2023, Valencia, Spain.

## Efficient Statistical Assessment of Neural Network Corruption Robustness. - NeurIPS 2021

K.T., T. Furon, M.Rousset. - 35th Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems, Dec 2021, Sydney (virtual), Australia.

# Évaluation statistique efficace de la robustesse de classifieurs. - CAID 2021 (In French)

K.T., T. Furon, M.Rousset, L.-M. Traonouez. - Conference on Artificial Intelligence for Defense, DGA, DGNUM, Ministère des Armées, Nov 2021, Rennes, France.

## TEACHING 2

## École Polytechnique

October 2019- January 2020

Tutorials for undergrad students covering advanced statistics and measure theory (45h in total).

## ACADEMIC AWARDS **Q**

Scholarship for academic excellence, 'Sophie Germain'

2019-2020

Masters Scholarship awarded by the Fondation Mathématiques Jacques Hadamard (FMJH)

Scholarship for academic excellence, 'PGSM'

2018-2019

Masters Scholarship awarded by the Paris Graduate School of Mathematics

## NON-ACADEMIC INTERESTS &

Music: Guitar & Piano

Sports: Calisthenics & Running

Travelling: Armenia-Belgium-England-Germany-Georgia-Morocco-Portugal-Tunisia-Turkey-Spain